Register of the Angolan subject collection, 1939-2001.
Hoover Institution Archives
Angolan subject collection,
1939-2001.
XX780
8 manuscript boxes, 5 phonorecords, 2 phonotape cassettes, 1 videotape cassette (3.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Electronic bulletins, pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, reports, communiqués, press releases, press summaries, clippings, other printed matter, and letters, relating to revolutionary movements in Angola, the establishment of Angolan independence, civil war, and political, economic and social conditions in Angola.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives. An increment was added in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Electronic bulletins, pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, reports, communiqués, press releases, press summaries, clippings, other printed matter, and letters, relating to revolutionary movements in Angola, the establishment of Angolan independence, civil war, and political, economic and social conditions in Angola.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Angola--History--Revolution, 1961-1975.; Angola--History--Civil War, 1975-; Phonorecords.; Phonotapes.; Video tapes.
Collection Contents
- GENERAL SUBJECT FILE, 1962-1994. (Box 1)
  Briefings, brochures, bulletins, clippings, communiques, flyers, newsletter, pamphlets, press releases, printed matter, and reports relating to political and economic conditions and human rights abuses in Angola
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1960-1991. (Box 2-4)
  Articles, brochures, bulletins, clippings, communiques, flyers, newsletters, pamphlets, press releases, printed matter, programs, reports, speeches and writings relating to political conditions and civil war in Angola
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1970-1983. (Record cabinet; Cassette cabinet; Tape cabinet)
  5 phonorecords relating to the revolutionary movements in Angola, 1970-1978; 2 phonotape cassettes relating to the liberation movement, 1970; and 1 videotape cassette relating to guerrilla warfare in Angola, 1983
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received after December 1994
- GENERAL SUBJECT FILE, 1962-1994
  - General (Box 1)
    - Brochure
    - Clippings
    - Printed matter
  - Angola Emergency Campaign
  - Foreign relations
    - General
    - Gulf Oil Company
      - General
      - Gulf Boycott Coalition
        - Leaflets and ephemera
        - Newsletters and press releases
    - Portugal
    - South Africa
    - United States
      - General
      - Central Intelligence Agency
      - Congressional Research Service publications
  - Human rights
    - General
    - Refugees
  - International support groups
    - Free Angola Campaign
    - Free Angola News Information Service
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1960-1991
  - General (Box 1)
    - Correspondence
    - Pamphlets and printed matter
  - Frente Nacional de Libertagco de Angola (FNLA - National Liberation Front of Angola) (Box 2)
    - General
    - Articles and clippings
    - Information bulletins issued by the Department of Information and the Department of Foreign Relations of the FNLA
    - Military report (Portuguese) by General Luz Cunha, "Estrutura Militar e Civil do ENLA - Doutrinagco Politica das Massas, " 1968
      - Speeches and writing by Holden Roberto, 1983
    - Gouvernement de la Republique Angolaise en Exil (GRAE - Government of the Republic of Angola in Exile)
      - General. Includes speech and petition by Holden Roberto
      - Articles and clippings
      - Communiques and press conferences
      - Proposed government programs
      - Reports
    - Movimento Popular de Libertagco de Angola (MPLA - People's Movement for the Liberation of Angola)
      - General. Includes interview of MPLA leader Dr. Agostinho Neto
      - Clippings
      - Communiques (Box 3)
        - Issued in Brazzaville and Leopoldville
        - Issued in Lusaka and Dar es Salaam
      - International support groups
        - General
        - Liberation Support Movement
      - Organizagco da Mulher Angolana (OMA - Organization of Angolan Women)
    - Parti Democrate de l'Angola (PDA - Democratic Party of Angola), 1963
    - Uniao das Populaceos de Angola (UPA - Union of the Populations of Angola)
      - General
      - Articles and clippings
      - Communiques, press conferences and memoranda. Includes press conference held by Holden Roberto
      - Information bulletins
      - Printed matter
        - UPA: a Voz da Revolucao
        - La Voix de la Nation Angolaise: a Voz da Nacao Angolana
    - Uniao Nacional para Independjncia Total de Angola (UNITA - National Union for the Total Independence of Angola)
      - General
      - Clippings and articles. Includes articles about Austrian journalist Fritz Sitte's travels with UNITA (Box 4)
      - Communiques and statements
        - 1971-1979
        - 1980-1983
        - 1984-1989
        - 1990-
      - Press release
      - Publications. Includes publications by the Free Angola Information Service
      - Reports
      - Speeches, writings and interviews by Jonas Savimbi
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1970-1983
  - Phonorecords (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
    - "Angola: A Vitoria e Certa!, " Songs of the Movimento Popular de Libertagco de Angola, 1970. Two records
    - "Angola: Forward, People's Power!" 1978 Roberto, Holden, President of Frente Nacional de Libertagco de Angola, speech, 1975 February 15
    - "Vitoria e Certa: Republica Popular de Angola, " n.d
  - Phonotape cassettes. (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
    - "Angola: A Vitoria e Certa!" Songs of the Movimento Popular de Libertagco de Angola, 1970. Two cassettes
  - Videotape cassette. (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
    - "The Lonely Guerrillas of Angola", tape of a television program relating to guerrilla warfare in Angola, 1983
- Incremental Materials (Box 5-8)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu